# Dan O'Neil

# **Full Stack Web Developer**

Philadelphia, PA | 440.708.3326 | <u>dhoneil@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:linkedin.com/in/dhoneil">linkedin.com/in/dhoneil</a>
GitHub: <a href="mailto:github.com/dandandanoneil.github.io">github.com/dandandanoneil.github.io</a>
Portfolio: <a href="mailto:dandandanoneil.github.io">dandandanoneil.github.io</a>

### summary

Web developer who excels at translating user requirements into full stack software architecture, building and debugging database queries, and developing algorithms and features that improve the user experience. Leader and team player with expertise in project planning and management, collaborative problem solving & creative thinking acquired over a 10 year career in theatre as a creative producer, director, casting director, and administrator. Seeking a job with opportunities to collaborate with more experienced developers.

## education

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development, February 2021

Penn LPS Coding Bootcamp, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

BFA, Theatre, 2010

Brind School of Theatre, The University of the Arts, Philadelphia, PA

## technical skills

JavaScript, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, jQuery, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Materialize, Java, GitHub

# selected projects

#### **Vinyl Destination**

github.com/rachelrosenstein/Vinyl-Destination vinyl-destination.herokuapp.com

A full-stack web application where users create an account to build/manage their music collection. The home page features dynamic content from last.fm's pop music charts, and users can either add albums to their collection using search results from the last.fm API, or manually.

JavaScript, MySQL, Node, Express, Handlebars, Sequelize, Passport, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap Framework

#### **Travel Companion**

github.com/dandandanoneil/travel-companion | dandandanoneil.github.io/travel-companion | A front-end web application that simulates the cultural experience of travel. Based on a user input (search, ask for a random city, or use my current location), the app makes external API calls to show tailored results from Goodreads, Open Movie Database, New York Times, and Harvard Art Museums.

JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Materialize Framework

#### **Secure Password Generator**

github.com/dandandanoneil/password-generator dandandanoneil.github.io/password-generator

A web application that generates secure, random passwords based on user inputs. User interface includes the ability to select what kinds of characters to include, easily copy the generated password to the clipboard, generate a new password with the same criteria, eliminate easily misread characters.

JavaScript, HTML5, Bootstrap Framework

# employment

Artistic Producer 2019- 2020

The Bearded Ladies Cabaret, Philadelphia, PA

- Managed the big picture and day-to-day spending for a \$250k pop-up cabaret venue and festival, bringing the project in under budget and nearly doubling projections for ticket sales and bar revenue.
- Implemented new budget tracking practices, allowing project artists and company leadership to make more informed spending and resource management decisions.
- Strengthened the community reach of artistic projects by building new relationships with community organizations, many of which introduced new or expanded funding possibilities.

# **Casting Director & Literary Manager**

2016-2019

Theatre Exile, Philadelphia, PA

- Facilitated script tracking system in season selection process, increasing scripts read by artistic staff.
- Successfully renegotiated Actors' Equity Association union agreement terms, allowing the company to continue producing high quality work without increasing budgets.

Artistic Assistant 2013-2015

Arden Theatre Company, Philadelphia, PA

- Introduced new actor resume management database, including document searchability, which saves artistic admin staff hours on each project, and is still in use.
- Boosted efficiency by transitioning artistic staff from paper calendars to a shared Google Calendar.

## **Assistant Director of Admissions**

2010-2013

The University of the Arts, Philadelphia, PA

- Launched partnership with Acceptd audition software to increase efficiency, gaining buy-in from
  performing arts faculty and staff, and managing integration of the software into the recruitment and
  admissions processes.
- Broadened recruitment travel to performing arts-specific recruiting events, encouraging cooperation between Admissions and College of Performing Arts recruitment and more efficient cross-department use of resources.

#### Freelance Creative Producer & Director

2009-2020

Detailed resume available on request

- Successfully negotiated an independent contract with Actors' Equity, enabling the hiring of top-tier acting talent.
- As staff casting director, successfully expanded the number of actors seen by the organization by increasing attendance at unified auditions, instituting open call auditions, and introducing the use of online audition listings.
- As box office manager for a large festival, led and managed a team of 20+ box office associates, including recruiting, hiring, and training new reps on Salesforce ticketing software and company processes.